$\bowtie CHUANXIA001@e.ntu.edu.sg$ 

• lyndonzheng

Homepage: https://www.chuanxiaz.com/

# Chuanxia Zheng

# Research Interests

My research centers on computer vision and machine learning. I am interested in creating a photorealistic virtual world. I have done a wide range of research on 2D image generation, completion and translation, 3D scene reconstruction, translation and interpretation.

### Education

	2017.08-2021.06
Ph.D. in Computer Science, SCSE Thesis: Synthesizing Photorealistic Images with Deep Generative Learning	
Advisor: Tat-Jen Cham and Jianfei Cai	2011.00.2015.00
Beihang University MA.E. in Automation Science	2014.09–2017.03
Thesis: Context-based Indoor Scene Understanding for Mobile Robot	
Advisor: Jianhua Wang and Weihai Chen	
	2010.09–2014.07
B.E. in Electronic and Information Engineering Ranked 2nd out of 100, Class of 2014	
Employment	
Monash University	2021.08-now
Research Fellow at Monash Research Institute of Science and Technology	
Research interests: 2D image generation and 3D generation  Huawei Research	2017.01-2017.06
Research assistant at Noah's Ark Lab	2017.01 2017.00
Research interests: face recognition and generation	
	2016.05–2016.09
Research Intern at Fundamental Research Center of Tencent Work on news recommendation	
Awards & Honors	
NTU Outstanding PhD Thesis Award	202
TMM Outstanding Reviewer Award	202
NTU Research Scholarship	201
First Prize Scholarship for Excellent Student	2015,201
Outstanding Graduate of Beijing	201
National Second Prize of the National Electronic Design Contest of China (Best one in B	Beijing) 201
Hanergy Scholarship Award ( <b>Top 1</b> %)	201
Siemens Scholarship Award ( <b>Top 1</b> %)	201
Press Coverage	
NTU News: NTU SCSE Outstanding PhD Thesis Award 2022	202
Zhuanzhi: How to create photo-realistic images? Ph.D. Thesis from Dr. Zheng	202
Sohu: AgileGAN — a new tool for creating stylized portraits	202

## Research Experience

VinAI, The national AI research Lab of Vietnam, Vietnam, Prof. Hung Bui

2021.11-now

Cooperator on high quality image generation and data compression

two papers submitted to NeurIPS

Department of Data Science & AI, Monash University, Australia, Prof. Jianfei cai

2021.08-now

Research interests: nature scene generation and completion

one paper accepted by CVPR, two papers submitted to ECCV, one paper submitted to SIGGRAPH ASIA

Mechanobiology Institue (MBI), NUS, Singapore, Prof. Lim Chwee Teck

2020.01-2021.10

Cooperator on cell nuclear generation

one paper submitted to Nature

Institute for Media Innovation (IMI), NTU, Singapore, Prof. Nadia Thalmann

2017.08-2021.06

Research interests: photorealistic image generation

seven papers accepted by CVPR(2), ECCV(1), ICCV(1), SIGGRAPH(1) and IJCV(2) IR&MCT Lab, Beihang University, China, Prof. Weihai Chen

2014.09-2017.03

Research interests: secne understanding and segmentation

#### **Publications**

- [15] Qianyi Wu, Xian Liu, Yuedong Chen, Kejie Li, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Jianfei Cai, and Jianming Zheng. Object-compositional neural implicit surfaces. In *Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision* (*ECCV*), 2022.
- [14] Yuedong Chen, Qianyi Wu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Sem2nerf: Converting single-view semantic masks to neural radiance fields. In *Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)*, 2022.
- [13] **Chuanxia Zheng**, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung. Bridging global context interactions for high-fidelity image completion. In *Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition*(CVPR), pages 11512–11522, June 2022.
- [12] Chuanxia Zheng, Duy-Son Dao, Guoxian Song, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Visiting the invisible: Layer-by-layer completed scene decomposition. *International Journal of Computer Vision (IJCV)*, 129(12):3195–3215, 2021.
- [11] Yujun Cai, Yiwei Wang, Yiheng Zhu, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, Junsong Yuan, Jun Liu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Sijie Yan, Henghui Ding, Xiaohui Shen, Ding Liu, and Nadia Magnenat Thalmann. A unified 3d human motion synthesis model via conditional variational auto-encoder. In *Proceedings of the International Conference on Computer Vision*(*ICCV*), pages 11645–11655, 2021.
- [10] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Pluralistic free-form image completion. *International Journal of Computer Vision (IJCV)*, 129(10):2786–2805, 2021.
- [9] Guoxian Song, Linjie Luo, Jing Liu, Wan-Chun Ma, Chunpong Lai, **Chuanxia Zheng**, and Tat-Jen Cham. Agilegan: stylizing portraits by inversion-consistent transfer learning. *ACM Transactions on Graphics* (*TOG*), 40(4):1–13, 2021.
- [8] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. The spatially-correlative loss for various image translation tasks. In *Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition(CVPR)*, pages 16407–16417, 2021.
- [7] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Pluralistic image completion. In *Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, pages 1438–1447, 2019.
- [6] Tianyi Zhang, Jingyi Yang, Chuanxia Zheng, Guosheng Lin, Jianfei Cai, and Alex C Kot. Task-in-all domain adaptation for semantic segmentation. In 2019 IEEE Visual Communications and Image Processing (VCIP), pages 1–4. IEEE, 2019.
- [5] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. T2net: Synthetic-to-realistic translation for solving single-image depth estimation tasks. In Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), pages 767–783, 2018.

- [4] Chuanxia Zheng, Jianhua Wang, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Multi-class indoor semantic segmentation with deep structured model. The Visual Computer (TVCJ), 34(5):735–747, 2018.
- [3] Jianhua Wang, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Learning aggregated features and optimizing model for semantic labeling. *The Visual Computer* (*TVCJ*), 33(12):1587–1600, 2017.
- [2] Chuanxia Zheng, Jianhua Wang, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Semantic segmentation based on aggregated features and contextual information. In 2016 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Biomimetics (ROBIO), pages 862–867. IEEE, 2016.
- [1] Jianhua Wang, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Learning contextual information for indoor semantic segmentation. In 2016 IEEE 11th Conference on Industrial Electronics and Applications (ICIEA), pages 1639–1644. IEEE, 2016.

#### Preprints

- [5] **Chuanxia Zheng**, Long Tung Vuong, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung. Movq: Modulating quantized vectors for high-fidelity image generation. *Under reviewer of NeurIPS*.
- [4] Long Tung Vuong, Trung Le, He Zhao, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Mehrtash Harandi, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung. Wasserstein vector quantization auto-encoder. *Under reviewer of NeurIPS*.
- [3] Yuzhu Ji, **Chuanxia Zheng**, and Tat-Jen Cham. One-shot human motion transfer via occlusion-robust flow prediction and neural texturing. *Under reviewer*.
- [2] **Chuanxia Zheng**, Guoxian Song, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, Linjie Luo, and Dinh Phung. High-quality pluralistic image completion via code sharing. *arXiv*.
- [1] Jyothsna Vasudevan\*, **Chuanxia Zheng**\*, James G. Wan, Tat-Jen Cham, Lim Chwee Teck, and Javier G. Fernandez. Determination of nuclear position by the arrangement of actin filaments using deep generative networks. *Under reviewer of Nature*.

#### Academic Services

Journal Reviewer	
IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence	TPAMI
International Journal of Computer Vision	IJCV
IEEE Transactions on Image Processing	TIP
IEEE Transactions on Multimedia (Outstanding Reviewer Award, 2021)	TMM
IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology	TCSVT
Computer Vision and Image Understanding	CVIU
The Visual Computer	TVCJ
Neural Computing and Applications	NCAA
Conference Reviewer	
CVPR, ECCV, ICLR, NeurIPS, SIGGRAPH, SIGGRAPH Asia, IJCAI, ACM MM, IROS	2022
CVPR, ICCV, ICLR, ACM MM	2021
CVPR, ECCV	2020
ICCV	2019
Talks	
Synthesizing Photorealsitic Scenes, Computer Vision & Geometry Group, ETH	2022.06
Synthesizing Photorealsitic Scenes, Graphics & Geometric Computing Laboratory, USTC	2022.01
Pluralistic Image Completion, Institute of Media Innovation, NTU	2019.11
Depth Estimation from Single 2D Image, Institute of Media Innovation, NTU	2018.06

# Teaching

Teaching Assistant, Advanced Digital Image Processing, Graduate, NTU	2018 – 2020
Teaching Assistant, Human-Computer Interaction, Undergraduate, NTU	2018 – 2020
Teaching Assistant, Engineering Mathematics, Undergraduate, NTU	2018–2019